<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <ABY_AbyssalSignalTheory.description>The colony has learned that reality answers certain shapes, frequencies and sacrificial loads with something far too structured to be random. This is not research into demons; it is the first successful study of the protocol by which the world can be made to answer back.</ABY_AbyssalSignalTheory.description>
  <ABY_AshboundCapacitance.description>Ash, residue and engineered chambers can store the first layer of ritual load without immediate collapse. It is a crude science, but crude science is still enough to industrialize danger.</ABY_AshboundCapacitance.description>
  <ABY_CircleStabilizerFrames.description>Primitive invocation can be survived with luck. Stable invocation requires frames, pylons and a language of force distribution that keeps the wound in the world from widening at the wrong moment.</ABY_CircleStabilizerFrames.description>
  <ABY_CrownCondensationArrays.description>Crown-class energy patterns demand condensers able to endure authority-bearing strain. These arrays do not make late ritual power safe; they merely make it available on purpose.</ABY_CrownCondensationArrays.description>
  <ABY_CrownContainmentArchitecture.description>At crown-tier load, containment stops being a matter of stronger materials and becomes a matter of hostile architecture. These designs aim to hold reality in shape long enough to work with strains that should already have become a disaster.</ABY_CrownContainmentArchitecture.description>
  <ABY_DominionGateBootstrapping.description>By combining late-tier sigil logic, crown-class containment and accumulated breach telemetry, the colony can attempt to bootstrap a dominion breach. The result is less a controlled opening than a deliberate invitation to an event that may outgrow its makers.</ABY_DominionGateBootstrapping.description>
  <ABY_ResonantLatticeStabilization.description>Further study reveals that a gate can be held not only by brute containment, but by tuned resonance. A proper lattice spreads stress through geometry and timing instead of letting it collapse into raw catastrophe.</ABY_ResonantLatticeStabilization.description>
  <ABY_RiftCapacitanceMatrices.description>Unstable ritual charge can be measured, redirected and packed through proper matrices. This turns the circle's electrical appetite from a liability into a disciplined part of gate control.</ABY_RiftCapacitanceMatrices.description>
</LanguageData>
