<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <ABY_AbyssalForge.description>An infernal-industrial forge built to process the trophies of the Abyss into weapons, implants and higher forms of access. The moment a colony begins using one, it stops merely resisting the intrusion and starts manufacturing its future out of enemy matter.</ABY_AbyssalForge.description>
  <ABY_AbyssalResidue.description>The basic material ash left behind when local matter survives contact with hostile law. Residue is not simple loot; it is proof that reality has already been bent hard enough to leave a usable scar.</ABY_AbyssalResidue.description>
  <ABY_ArchonBeast.description>A domainal war-node clad in abyssal carapace and driven by an overbound reactor-heart. The beast is not just a monster; it is a mobile fragment of hostile administration, sent to test whether a colony deserves harsher answers.</ABY_ArchonBeast.description>
  <ABY_ArchonOfRupture.description>A crowned rupture administrator in living form. Its body is only the visible shell of a local law that arrives to rewrite the battlefield, summon support and judge whether the world is ready for deeper intrusion.</ABY_ArchonOfRupture.description>
  <ABY_ArchonOverrideAmpoule.description>A combat ampoule distilled from stolen archon routines. For a brief interval it forces the body into a cleaner, harder and less human pattern of battle before the backlash catches up.</ABY_ArchonOverrideAmpoule.description>
  <ABY_ArchonSigil.description>A sealed archon-class access sigil. It records that an archon-tier manifestation has been endured, fixed and made repeatable through industrial ritual procedure.</ABY_ArchonSigil.description>
  <ABY_ArchonTendonSpine.description>A reinforced spinal and tendon lattice patterned after archon assault frames. Once installed, the user moves less like a human body under strain and more like a weapon platform obeying a superior combat rhythm.</ABY_ArchonTendonSpine.description>
  <ABY_AshboundCapacitorModule.description>A low-tier capacitor module that stores ritual load in ash-packed chambers and residue glass. It does not make the circle safe; it only makes the first layer of danger reusable.</ABY_AshboundCapacitorModule.description>
  <ABY_CrownCondenserModule.description>A crown-tier condenser that packs hostile ritual charge into dense, disciplined storage. It belongs to operators who have stopped asking whether the gate should exist and started asking how much more of it can be forced open.</ABY_CrownCondenserModule.description>
  <ABY_CrownOfRupture.description>A crown-grade artifact that offers more than strength: it offers rank. To wear it is to accept a fragment of hostile right-of-rule and risk becoming an interface for something far above the battlefield.</ABY_CrownOfRupture.description>
  <ABY_CrownStabilizerModule.description>A high-tier containment pylon built for crown-class strain. Its whole purpose is to hold the world in shape while the ritual asks more of reality than reality was meant to endure.</ABY_CrownStabilizerModule.description>
  <ABY_CrudeStabilizerModule.description>A primitive frame for holding the circle's geometry together through low-tier invocations. It exists to keep early rituals survivable, not clean.</ABY_CrudeStabilizerModule.description>
  <ABY_DominionAnchor_Breach.description>An anchor tuned to widen the wound itself. It accelerates the crisis, strengthens follow-up manifestations and pushes the map closer to admitted territory.</ABY_DominionAnchor_Breach.description>
  <ABY_DominionAnchor_Drain.description>A dominion anchor specialized in feeding on local infrastructure. It drinks power, fouls systems and turns the colony's own grid into ritual fuel.</ABY_DominionAnchor_Drain.description>
  <ABY_DominionAnchor_Suppression.description>A dominion anchor that blankets the battlefield in hostile suppressive logic. While it stands, static defenses and clean firing solutions become increasingly unreliable.</ABY_DominionAnchor_Suppression.description>
  <ABY_DominionAnchor_Ward.description>A warding anchor that distributes protective authority through the breach lattice. It exists to remind the colony that the crisis is not one target, but a cooperating machine of intrusion.</ABY_DominionAnchor_Ward.description>
  <ABY_DominionCrownShard.description>A shard of dominion-grade authority recovered from a contained Great Infernal Gate staging. Such fragments are not merely rare materials; they are damaged pieces of the Abyss's own administrative right.</ABY_DominionCrownShard.description>
  <ABY_DominionGateCore.description>The Great Infernal Gate made visible as a battlefield object. In this package it is still an outer breach stage rather than the full boss arena, but it already behaves like hostile infrastructure with anchors, pulses and the right to escalate.</ABY_DominionGateCore.description>
  <ABY_DominionSigil.description>A late-tier sigil that grants the right to begin a dominion-class breach sequence. In the current package it is the formal authorization to bootstrap the Great Infernal Gate staging layer before the colony learns to enter it.</ABY_DominionSigil.description>
  <ABY_EmberHound.description>A fast breach-hunter bred to shatter firing lines and run down exposed targets. Ember hounds embody the Abyss at full pursuit: not brute force, but relentless tempo and predatory pressure.</ABY_EmberHound.description>
  <ABY_EmberHoundSigil.description>A bound access mark used to reproduce the ember hound encounter pattern. Sigils are not trophies; they are sealed rights to repeat a form of invasion the colony has already survived once.</ABY_EmberHoundSigil.description>
  <ABY_HeraldCarapaceMesh.description>A folded subdermal mesh of herald-grade plates and heat channels. It does not turn flesh into armor so much as persuade the body to accept a more abyssal standard of durability.</ABY_HeraldCarapaceMesh.description>
  <ABY_HeraldCoreFragment.description>A splinter of higher-order abyssal architecture torn from a heraldic node. It is too structured to be dismissed as scrap and too dangerous to be mistaken for an ordinary component.</ABY_HeraldCoreFragment.description>
  <ABY_HeraldEye.description>A boss-grade ocular implant that replaces sight with disciplined infernal acquisition logic. It grants more than vision: it teaches the bearer to read battle through hostile precision.</ABY_HeraldEye.description>
  <ABY_HexgunBolt.description>A compact infernal bolt that carries both heat and tracking malice. Even a near miss feels like a firing solution being written over the target.</ABY_HexgunBolt.description>
  <ABY_HexgunRelaySigil.description>A retired relay sigil from an earlier invocation pattern. Existing copies remain as legacy access marks for compatibility, but the current circle no longer treats them as a frontline rite.</ABY_HexgunRelaySigil.description>
  <ABY_HexgunThrall.description>A chained gun-servitor engineered for disciplined breach volleys. Hexgun thralls prove the Abyss does not create only beasts and horrors; it can also manufacture doctrine, obedience and line infantry.</ABY_HexgunThrall.description>
  <ABY_ImpPortal.description>A minor portal node through which the Abyss feeds expendable assault forms into local reality. It is not a grand gate, only the kind of wound a colony starts seeing once the world learns how to answer back.</ABY_ImpPortal.description>
  <ABY_OblivionChoir.description>A heavy annihilation cannon that chambers choir cells into a moving abyssal core. It is less a firearm than a carried breach event, engineered to punish clusters, armor and static positions with ritualized overkill.</ABY_OblivionChoir.description>
  <ABY_OblivionChoirCell.description>A sealed magazine cell containing a stabilized choir-seed. Once fired, the charge unfolds toward the logic of a miniature breach-heart before collapsing in violent release.</ABY_OblivionChoirCell.description>
  <ABY_OblivionChoirCoreProjectile.description>A condensed choir-heart in transit. It flies like a controlled rupture and arrives like a small local catastrophe.</ABY_OblivionChoirCoreProjectile.description>
  <ABY_ResonantStabilizerModule.description>A tuned stabilizer lattice that spreads gate stress through a controlled resonance pattern. It is the difference between a desperate breach and an engineered one.</ABY_ResonantStabilizerModule.description>
  <ABY_RiftBlade.description>A short rift-edge melee weapon that opens flesh and armor along unstable seams. It is not elegant; it is a portable argument that material integrity can be renegotiated at knife range.</ABY_RiftBlade.description>
  <ABY_RiftCapacitorModule.description>A tuned capacitance block that reshapes unstable abyssal load into cleaner breach pulses. It is built for circles that have advanced beyond crude containment and begun to traffic in repeatable rupture geometry.</ABY_RiftCapacitorModule.description>
  <ABY_RiftCarbine.description>A rapid abyssal carbine built for disciplined suppression and medium-range pressure. Its bursts feel industrial rather than improvised, as if the weapon was designed by a doctrine that values intrusion over recoil.</ABY_RiftCarbine.description>
  <ABY_RiftCarbineBeamBurst.description>A rift-burn burst that carries more breach geometry than visible mass. The shot is brief, but the wound remembers being opened from the wrong side.</ABY_RiftCarbineBeamBurst.description>
  <ABY_RiftImp.description>A low-order breach form built for speed, saturation and disposable violence. Rift imps are the first language of a real opening: cheap, fast, and terrifying in numbers.</ABY_RiftImp.description>
  <ABY_RupturePortal.description>A hotter and more disciplined portal breach that carries mid-tier hostility instead of mere noise. Where these appear, intrusion has advanced from harassment to deliberate pressure.</ABY_RupturePortal.description>
  <ABY_SigilVault.description>A reinforced archive for bound sigils. It keeps rights of invocation organized, visible and recoverable instead of letting crown-marked tokens vanish into ordinary storage.</ABY_SigilVault.description>
  <ABY_SpecterLashAnchor.description>The anchor seed fired by a Specter Lash projector. On impact it writes a temporary point of hostile ownership into the target and lets the tether do the rest.</ABY_SpecterLashAnchor.description>
  <ABY_SpecterLashProjector.description>A residue-fed tether projector that anchors a target and lashes it with repeated infernal pulses. Instead of delivering one clean hit, it turns the victim into the centerline of an ongoing execution process.</ABY_SpecterLashProjector.description>
  <ABY_SummoningCircle.description>The first machine of direct negotiation with the Abyss. To the untrained eye it is a ritual circle; to an engineer it is a containment interface; to whatever listens beyond the breach, it is an invitation.</ABY_SummoningCircle.description>
  <ABY_UltraPlasmaBeamBurst.description>A stretched ultra-plasma discharge tuned for concentrated armor-breaking impact. The beam is clean only in appearance; underneath it is still a coerced rupture phenomenon.</ABY_UltraPlasmaBeamBurst.description>
  <ABY_UltraPlasmaBolt.description>A dense cyan plasma bolt carrying breach-conditioned heat. It burns like advanced energy fire and destabilizes like something that should never have fit inside a rifle.</ABY_UltraPlasmaBolt.description>
  <ABY_UltraPlasmaRifle.description>A late-tier plasma rifle rebuilt around herald-derived breach telemetry. It projects disciplined cyan overfire with extreme armor penetration and leaves the target struggling to contain what was forced through it.</ABY_UltraPlasmaRifle.description>
  <ABY_UnstableBreachSigil.description>A crude breach right hammered into usable form before proper control exists. It opens danger cheaply and answers only reluctantly to containment.</ABY_UnstableBreachSigil.description>
</LanguageData>
