<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
  <ABY_DominionSliceBastion.label>dominion bastion fragment</ABY_DominionSliceBastion.label>
  <ABY_DominionSliceBastion.description>A jagged fragment of dominion architecture, used to frame the slice as a shattered machine-temple rather than a copied void finale.</ABY_DominionSliceBastion.description>
  <ABY_DominionSliceSpire.label>dominion spire</ABY_DominionSliceSpire.label>
  <ABY_DominionSliceSpire.description>A crown-spire of the dominion slice. It marks routes, breaks sight lines and reinforces the feeling of a hostile infernal processing chamber.</ABY_DominionSliceSpire.description>
  <ABY_DominionSliceSigilPad.label>dominion sigil pad</ABY_DominionSliceSigilPad.label>
  <ABY_DominionSliceSigilPad.description>A plated sigil dais used to mark entry, extraction, anchor and heart positions inside the dominion slice.</ABY_DominionSliceSigilPad.description>
  <ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Seal.label>seal anchor</ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Seal.label>
  <ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Seal.description>A dominion anchor that holds the Crown-Heart under a shielding law. While any seal anchor remains, the heart rejects direct damage.</ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Seal.description>
  <ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Choir.label>choir anchor</ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Choir.label>
  <ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Choir.description>A dominion anchor that synchronizes the slice with hostile reinforcements. Left alone, it accelerates the rhythm of incoming support waves.</ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Choir.description>
  <ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Law.label>law anchor</ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Law.label>
  <ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Law.description>A dominion anchor that sharpens the geometry of the slice itself. While it stands, the heart pulses become more punishing.</ABY_DominionSliceAnchor_Law.description>
  <ABY_DominionSliceHeart.label>crown-heart of the gate</ABY_DominionSliceHeart.label>
  <ABY_DominionSliceHeart.description>The unique crown-heart embedded in the dominion slice. It is not a reused portal core: it is the revealed command-organ of the encounter, exposed only after the dominion anchors are destroyed.</ABY_DominionSliceHeart.description>
  <ABY_DominionSlicePerimeterWall.label>dominion perimeter wall</ABY_DominionSlicePerimeterWall.label>
  <ABY_DominionSlicePerimeterWall.description>A dense dominion barrier segment fused into the slice boundary. It exists to deny escape through the map edge and hold the encounter inside the infernal machine-domain.</ABY_DominionSlicePerimeterWall.description>
</LanguageData>
